Gareth Bizley

Android Developer

3/1 43 Queen Elizabeth Gardens GLASGOW, G5 OUH +44 7552 307 536 gaz.biz@gmail.com

Introduction

I've been working as an Android dev for almost 6 years. I'm a very fast learner and work extremely well with other team members. I enjoy both learning and passing knowledge on to others. I am an avid fantasy reader, film buff & gamer. I believe I have a few more years to round my skills out as a senior but am always looking for opportunities to capitalise on my soft skills and eventually move to a team lead role.

Development

I'm a big fan of everything Android Jetpack. Leveraging these tools allows me to deliver with both speed and confidence. I am most comfortable with modern MVVM/MVI architectures but have worked on projects that use many different approaches. I embrace TDD in all work I do. I enjoy learning from and mentoring all levels of devs and have spent the last 4 years involved in a mentoring program with Glasgow inner city highschools.

Skills

Android Libraries	Languages	Other tools
 Android Jetpack Dagger/Hilt DataBinding Compose Cucumber Google Truth JUnit LiveData Mockito Proguard Retrofit RxJava 	 Kotlin Java JSON XML HTML SQL Groovy 	 Jira Confluence Git Postman UML Android Studio Gradle TDD BDD Bitrise Firebase Google Console

Experience

AUGUST 2022 - PRESENT

Deliveroo, fully remote - Android Developer

Main skills: Kotlin|Groovy|XML|Bitrise

Worked on a new app for the grocery delivery space.

- Owned the creation of a release test process. Greenfield app had required several hot fixes in production prior to this, and has required none since.
- Worked closely with the localisation team to implement a standardised process for app localisation.
- Worked closely with legal teams and product managers to ensure readiness for google play store release.
- Worked with events reporting teams to ensure their additions to the android app played nicely with existing architecture and design paradigms.

JUNE 2020 - AUGUST 2022

BBC, Glasgow - Senior Android Developer

Main skills: Kotlin|Java|XML|Compose|Interop|TDD

Maintained and enhanced an authentication library used by all BBC Android apps & later worked on iPlayer & Sounds android apps.

- Transitioned into a new team spread across the UK mid pandemic and was up and running with first code commits within a week
- Quickly took on a leadership role as the key android developer within the auth library squad
- Worked with apprentices in a mentoring role
- Owned the bulk of engineering decisions within the authentication library
- Gained extensive experience working with legacy code
- Identified, actioned and led work to shore up existing security flaws

JANUARY 2019 - JUNE 2020

Scottish Power, Glasgow - Android Developer

Iberdrola Ireland & Scottish Power apps - Play store

- Took the role of 'Squad Leader' for the mobile development team, assisting in story readiness and high level technical solutions
- Took several features from initial pitch through UX review and API design to implementation and delivery in a fast paced environment
- Maintained and built upon 2 live apps with over 250k users
- Boosted code coverage of unit testing in both projects
- Contributed to production code within a few weeks after upskilling with an unfamiliar bleeding edge tech stack
- Interfacing with multiple 3rd party SDK's
- Onboarding and mentoring juniors, mid level and new starts
- Documentation of technical solutions (UML and plain text)

Processing of payments and 3rd party appointment bookings in app

NOVEMBER 2016 - NOVEMBER 2018

Resdiary, Glasgow - Junior Android Developer

Resdiary app - Play Store

- Assisted a small, inexperienced team in releasing their first app to play store
- Maintained the first app release and laid the groundwork for a more complex application while learning RXJava and Kotlin
- As a one person team, refactored legacy app to reduce crash rate by 50%

JANUARY 2008 - MARCH 2016

Settlers Tavern, Margaret River - Assistant General Manager

- Running an extremely busy restaurant serving 700 1000 meals per day during peak season
- Rostered, trained and managed up to 40 FOH staff at a time, keeping wage costs to a minimum
- Managed the venue's live music program for 2 years, during which we won best live music venue in Australia

Education

JULY 2012 - JULY 2017

RMIT - Bachelor of Computer Studies

Focus on programming, software architecture and agile methodologies. Minor in Economics from University of South Australia. Finished with a HD average.

Certificates

- Amazon Web Services Essentials
- Coaching Conversations
- Effective Conversations
- Network Fundamentals
- Mentor Training
- Behavior Driven Development
- Advanced TDD

References

Chris Vaughan - Principal Android Developer, BBC

chris.vaughan01@bbc.co.uk

Moyi Liu - Senior Android Developer